<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smiley Lab</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 14:30:10 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 14:30:10 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Distractions in times of a Global Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I noticed that the New York Times changed a lot after the birth of COVID-19. Every day, it shared films that we can binge-watch at home, along with new recipes, books, and even video games. This “At Home” section stayed on the front page along with the regular serious articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was strange to me how a newspaper emphasizes that “not losing your mind” is important, telling me that distractions are necessary right now. It surely felt human, but I did not buy that idea. I would rather “enrich my mind” by using the hours at home to do something meaningful. My school switched entirely to online learning until the end of this school year, and I was sure that there would be myriad ways to diversify my indoor life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my goal to create meaning resulted in sitting in front of my computer all day long. Making music with my friends required a keyboard, GarageBand, and Adobe Premiere Pro. Working on Data Science projects meant researching online and crunching data with Atom. Running outside with a mask was the only outdoor activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero commute time gave me great flexibility in my schedule. It was not long ago when I minimized such “unproductive” time, listening to Ted Talks on the way to school and flipping over Hanzi Flashcards while returning. But I realized now that physically being in different settings has always ventilated my mind so that it can be filled with refreshing new tasks. Instead of enjoying the maximum productivity that I hoped for, I started looking into the recommendations by the New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fulfilled the need to unwind here and there—ventilating my mind—with screen time again. Youtube, Netflix, iPad games, and more. They were like energy-boost drinks that have an immediate effect, and I didn’t need to move an inch to enjoy them. My desk had all I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../post-images/2020-6-16-distractions-covid-19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My workspace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only if these energy drinks were not addictive…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly lost the sense of distinction between energy-boosts and productive work. Walking and working were two very different things before the virus, but everything now was under the broad category of “screen time.” After hours pass in any given day, it became too common for me to summarise what I have achieved. When I went through History in Google Chrome a week ago, the redness of Youtube and Netflix dominated the website list. The elegance of the New York Times logo and WaitButWhy faded. I even lost a sense of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to justify my relationship with distractions every day. I am in the middle of a serious global pandemic, and as the New York Times said, let’s just not “lose my mind.” What else can I do? What else &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dissatisfaction with myself grew daily as I tried to enlighten the day with an endless array of momentary entertainment. Distractions seemed to be almost paralyzing me, removing any space for my mind to wander. Does “not losing my mind” mean constantly distracting it? This feels wrong. Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the New York Times woke me up. On its front page one day, I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/12/opinion/sunday/black-america-racism-refugee.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Opinion&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot;&gt;a powerful and moving article.&lt;/a&gt; It was a personal reflection by Tiffanie Drayton, who fled the US due to unstoppable racism and the danger that black citizens face in the country. A mixture of emotions hit me as I visualized the heart-wrenching descriptions of protests and the ongoing attacks against black Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as racism was “too much” for her to bear, the shame I felt about myself overwhelmed me. I did not know anything about George Floyd and the reasons why people are on the streets. I did not know how the “Black Lives Matter” movement sprung up. I had to google everything up because the author simply did not need to define these current events, knowing that it is already in the minds of millions. While these people were heroically calling for change, I was stuck in my room disconnected from the world, only plugged into irrelevant distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I was like a newsboy. I closely followed the upcoming US Election, and I watched every single Democratic Debate from start to finish. I marveled at the endorsement of two candidates by the New York Times. I also watched Joe Biden going up and down, finally securing his place. The more I stayed away from current news, the more I became indifferent to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unwinding has become more important than ever during this stressful global crisis, but I believe that it should not numb our attention to the outside world. For a data science journalist, current events are sources of inspiration. Too often, distractions also interfere with the momentum of our goals and daily tasks. Writing is a stellar example because it requires us to spend time with sustained and focused effort, which can easily become daunting once distractions take over our minds. The need to think deeply becomes tedious, urging us to visit Youtube for short-and-sweet entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I am distracted, the less I am myself. Distractions are important to unload stress, but I indeed went too far.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/distractions-in-times-of-covid-19</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/distractions-in-times-of-covid-19</guid>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mr.Blue Sky covered by Jazz Frustrations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A team of four musicians, including me, created a jazz version of Mr.Blue Sky, composed by the legendary Electric Light Orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent over a month recording ourselves at home and compiling videos! It was so much fun for me to sync the videos on Adobe Premier Pro and add more parts as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was finished on May 16th, and the video was showcased in our school’s last assembly of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1N0nwvssBpp4gJwAtQbCKuwrMj7YJtBE1/preview&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1N0nwvssBpp4gJwAtQbCKuwrMj7YJtBE1/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;The link to the video is here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/music-with-friends</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/music-with-friends</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ideal Today and Actual Today</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../snippets/2020-6-15-dream-and-today.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/dream-and-today</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/dream-and-today</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper Money and Pennies. And Aliens.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../snippets/2020-6-9-money-and-pennies.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/paper-money-and-pennies</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/paper-money-and-pennies</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Search Terms &quot;Fake&quot; vs. &quot;Fact&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;special-article&quot;&gt;Special Article!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very long drawing, so please click on the link to view this image!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much long it is, I am excited to show this to you. It uses Google Trends to see the popularity of two words over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../snippets/2020-6-9-fake-vs-fact-2016-drawing.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tinker with the data by yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=today%205-y&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;q=fact,fake&quot;&gt;Link to the Comparison of “Fake” and “Fact” trends, in the US.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily change the search terms or remove one to suit your needs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading this article.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/fake-vs-fact-2016</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/fake-vs-fact-2016</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Interconnectedness of the World - Grade 9 Assignment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../snippets/2020-6-8-about-interconnectedness.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/about-interconnectedness</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/about-interconnectedness</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Philosophical and Ethical Thoughts on the Human Genome Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the thoughts on the Human Genome Project?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/philosophical-ethical-implications-human-genome-project</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/philosophical-ethical-implications-human-genome-project</guid>
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Boredom</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../snippets/2020-06-06-boredom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/about-boredom</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/about-boredom</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is the Human Genome Project?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the first thing scientists did to tackle the rapidly-evolving COVID-19? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They decoded the virus. It is often known as “genomic sequencing.” After China shared the first cases with the world in late December, scientists gathered to identify the full sequence of the coronavirus. Researchers from France, Korea, and other nations followed suit soon after. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genomic sequencing works as a foundational blueprint for scientists. The sequence is used as a reference when developing diagnostic tests and determining potential treatments. 
While the genomic sequence for COVID-19 quickly became a shared resource of the globe, such a process was more complicated a few decades ago, when the United States kickstarted an ambitious plan to decode a person. Yes, the “human” genome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worthwhile to revisit the history behind the project that pushed us into the grand “era of the genome.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following major technological advances in the 1970s, the notion of decoding a human got more feasible for scientists. Some critics assumed that functions of genes cannot be ever studied through their sequence, but a combination of potential scientific merit and public interest pushed the idea forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Department of Energy (DOE) and National Institute of Health (NIH) launched the “Human Genome Project” on October 1st, 1990, with the rough completion year of 2005. At the time, they did not expect that they will finish two entire years in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../post-images/D5ADBFBF-BB29-46B9-88A5-FA70A80FE9A1 1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their big aim was to determine all genes and sequence nucleotides of the human genome, and also create databases to store information. But another important aspect was considering the philosophical and ethical issues, so roughly five percent of the budget was allocated towards this cause. Philosopher Eric T. Juengst was the director of this program. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of sequencing the genome right away, the team built genetic and physical “maps” first. In essence, DNA clones were replicated for sequencing, and polymorphic markers were used to target specific “chromosomal regions.” Then, they tested genomic sequencing on smaller organisms before moving to the more complex human genome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The task of sequencing the human genome stretched outside the US, where France and the United Kingdom funded their own research institutes. The Sanger Centre of the UK opened in 1993, which received support from the Wellcome Trust and Medical Research Council. Japan and China also jumped in soon after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the team noticed a growing interest from the private sector in genome sequencing, such as the Celera Genomics. It proposed a distinctive way of sequencing, called the “whole-genome shotgun method,” which breaks the entire genome with high-frequency sound waves into many smaller pieces of DNA, sequence them, and reassemble the sequences with supercomputers by mapping the clones to chromosomes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The public sector and Celera used different approaches, but they achieved the same result: sequencing roughly 3.2 billion base pairs. The US President Bill Clinton, DOE, and other scientists announced that the project has been completed in 2000, but the results actually had many gaps. Three years later, despite less public interest due to war and terrorism, the project officially came to a close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sequencing of the genome was truly an international effort. Six countries contributed 16 centers in total. Along the process, efficient methods of sequencing entire genomes were created and tested. Scientists were able to give partial credit to the initial assumption because the structure of the genome could provide limited insights into its function. Still, the project opened a new window of opportunities for the broad field of biology. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is curious to see if the Human Genome Project has provided equal opportunities for all parts of the world. How has the project accelerated medicine development, and is there any aspect that is left behind? If the publicity of the genomic sequence spurred innovation, what are the policies of the beneficiaries of the modern world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I dive into these questions, I will write about the role of the sub-group that worked on the philosophical and ethical implications of the project. I hope to look at the visions they created and how they compare with the current society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Research Paper Used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gannett, Lisa, “The Human Genome Project”, The Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy (Winter 2019 Edition), Edward N. Zalta (ed.).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/what-is-human-genome-project</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/what-is-human-genome-project</guid>
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paradox of Computers for People in Need</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“I have a little announcement,” I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a regular lunch meeting for my
service club. I pulled out my MacBook,
walked to the podium—an English
classroom is our venue—and began
talking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am happy you had fun in AlHurriyah! If you couldn’t go, we all can
revisit the school sometime. Sixty fifthgraders greeted us, and we checked if
there is a vacant room for computers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sixty?” Some gasped in unison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Exactly. We can teach more than
sixty, or even the whole school.
Sugata Mitra’s ‘Hole in the Wall’
experiment proved the power of a
single computer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But I want to share another story.
Last week, there was a three-hour trip
to a hilly village in Sentul. One girl I
met is re-reading her old comic books
because school is too far away.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our advisor raised his eyebrows. I
took a breath and continued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Here’s the dilemma: five computers
for ten out-of-school children in the
village or five-hundred students in AlHurriyah. What’s better?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Managing computers located threehours away would be hard, though.”
one member commented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Definitely. But here’s a plan called
‘Computer Drive.’ Like a delivery
service…” I spoke for another ten
minutes, but I knew I lost the
audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dilemma, in fact, left me clueless
for days. After researching and
thinking, I passionately supported the
school-less children. Although it didn’t
pass, it was a profound battle between
many and few, far and near, and
ultimately, my values and experiences
of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this dilemma ever answerable?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/plugged-in-paradox-of-computers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/plugged-in-paradox-of-computers</guid>
        
        <category>jis</category>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
