<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Great Point Alert</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 12:04:58 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 12:04:58 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Rating</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/snippets/2020-6-25-ratings.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/ratings</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/ratings</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Blank Sheet of Paper</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/snippets/2020-6-25-blank-sheet-of-paper.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/blank-sheet-of-paper</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/blank-sheet-of-paper</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Aral Sea</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/snippets/2020-6-24-the-aral-sea.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/the-aral-sea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/the-aral-sea</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Perhaps, Genuineness is No Longer that Simple.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/snippets/2020-6-23-genuineness-not-simple.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/genuineness-not-simple</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/genuineness-not-simple</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Elevator</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/snippets/2020-6-22-the-elevator.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/the-elevator</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/the-elevator</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/snippets/2020-6-20-the-world.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/the-world</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/the-world</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning How to Write with Integrity - with the New York Times Ethical Journalism Handbook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I discovered a shocking news. It is not ‘breaking’ news, but I learn that a famous pop-science Youtuber got accused in 2019 for plagiarising when making his videos and submitting his own research paper. He also gained immense profits by making an interaction-based course (200 dollars to enter) that used outside sources without giving proper credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His main areas of interests are artificial intelligence, machine learning, and blockchain, and I used to admire his work. His Youtube videos were funny, focused, and fast-paced. He seemed to be a rockstar who is eager and confident to share all the knowledge he has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-question-and-concerns&quot;&gt;My Question and Concerns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This news made me wonder: How can I share my knowledge or research with the world with integrity? How can I avoid plaigiarism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even when writing this article, I did not know if I am allowed to write the name of this YouTuber. Am I going to offend him in any way? As a student running a personal blog, are the boundaries of my writing different from the New York Times?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I am developing this blog every day, I felt strongly that writing well is not enough. Let’s use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/editorial-standards/ethical-journalism.html&quot;&gt;New York Times Ethical Journalism Handbook&lt;/a&gt; to learn the standards of my favourite news outlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also used its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/editorial-standards/guidelines-on-integrity.html&quot;&gt;“Guidelines on Integrity”&lt;/a&gt; to gain further insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../post-images/2020-6-17-ethical-journalism.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, much of the content in the Handbook regards to the relationship between the staff and the outside world, which includes news sources, people, and competitors. I, as an individual blogger, will focus mainly on “Open Source Investigations,” where Internet is the outside world. Therefore, it is important to summarise anything that deals with the use of online sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;participation-in-public-life&quot;&gt;“Participation in Public Life”&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One powerful remark from the Times is that “journalists have no place on the playing fields of politics.” They should not do anything that might hint their political interests or views, such as donating for a specific candidate. Because journalists and politicians usually balance each other, I am thrilled to be a journalist who looks at societal problems. Op-Ed columnists enjoy a little bit more freedom because it is their job to express opinions. I want to be vocal, but at the same time, I want to maintain neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting how the Times has full-time “standards editors,” who ensures that no staff member goes outside the boundary set by the Handbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the section that is repeated over and over:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those in doubt about contributions should consult their supervisors and the standards editor or the deputy editorial page editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shows that I also should seek advice from adults, like my parents. I am a teenager after all, so it is important to clear out any ambiguities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I did not get much information on how to properly credit others when writing articles. The Handbook mainly focused on behavioural expectations. Perhaps the reason is that much of the content published by the Times is original, using the products of physical investigations. However, I see a lot of links within some articles, especially those that contain statistics, so I hope to understand why columnists do not include a “Works Cited” page. Let’s see if the “Guidelines on Integrity” page can help me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../post-images/2020-6-17-guidelines-on-integrity.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;quotations&quot;&gt;Quotations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should not clean up quotations. If I include quotes from online sources, the reader must be sure that the words between the quotation marks are &lt;strong&gt;exactly&lt;/strong&gt; as they were written. The Times says that “approximate” quotations can “undermine readers’ trust” in the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;other-peoples-reporting&quot;&gt;Other People’s Reporting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I use “facts gathered by any other organization,” I must attribute them. Unless I witness events myself or complete an original research, whenever I use an outside source, attribution is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My question is, is it enough to provide &lt;strong&gt;links&lt;/strong&gt; to the sources? I am familiar with putting a ‘Works Cited’ section for all the essays I have completed in high school, but I do not know the standards in terms of writing articles. I never see this section in the articles of the Times. Columnists only put links. Does this method apply to me as well?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to find this out soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;corrections&quot;&gt;Corrections&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have seen, the Times never arbitrary changes the article itself when there are errors or misinformation. It always puts a ‘Correction’ section at the top of the article, with a brief explanation and date. I will do this as well. If anything I write about is misleading, I will put up this section to maintain integrity and acknowledge my mistake. Simply altering the article will be viewed as an attempt to conceal it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;some-thoughts-on-plagiarism&quot;&gt;Some Thoughts on Plagiarism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two resources studied above did not talk about plagiarism. However, I think this topic is one of the most important ones I need to learn. Instead of writing an essay about it here, I want to express some brief thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pop-science YouTuber, as mentioned before, made some of his videos using online sources without giving any credit that viewers can discover. He only changed grammar and a few words to avoid being labelled as “plagiarising,” sounding as if what he is saying is perfectly owned by him. When I was watching his videos, I thought he digested every concept so well that words simply comes out of his mouth naturally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wrote the names of authors he referred to only in an almost non-discoverable README file. The only explanation that makes sense to me is that he wanted to seem like an all-knowing educator. There is no doubt that his behaviors are inappropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must include visible citations whenever I include quotes or paraphrase information. When I summarise a research paper, it is absolute basics to include a proper MLA citation at the end of the article and include inline citations whenever necessary. I learned all these skills in Grade 9 and 10, so this should not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plagiarism can quickly undermine one’s reputation. It does not hurt to be careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the idea that these Handbooks are read by every single staff member of the Times, as well as new employees just coming in. I admire the standards it set, and I am empowered to follow them when I am developing this blog. Although I am the only chief editor of my blog, the Internet should be treated with neutrality and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time, I want to check out the “New York Times Stylebook,” which I think will delve deeper into &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; columnists write. But as of now, I am too eager to jump into researching and crunching data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/learning-to-write-with-integrity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/learning-to-write-with-integrity</guid>
        
        <category>howto</category>
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Work and Rest during COVID-19 Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/snippets/2020-6-16-work-rest-covid-19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/work-rest-covid-19</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/work-rest-covid-19</guid>
        
        <category>creatives</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Should I Read Research Papers? (No PhD Needed!)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A big part of this blog will be reading research papers and sharing what I learned, including a brief summary along with key insights. I believe that reading papers is the surefire way to stay updated on the latest developments and gain valuable knowledge. They have value that goes beyond simply studying textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this current world where I am not allowed to go out, research papers are the best way to keep learning. From data science to biology to artificial intelligence, the catalog of research papers is constantly evolving, and I can’t wait to dive into the exciting field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched an incredibly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SHTOI0KtZnU&quot;&gt;helpful video by Siraj Raval&lt;/a&gt;, who is passionate about the field of machine learning, artificial intelligence, and more. I am putting a summary of what he suggested in the video, which I hope will be useful to others as well. All the credit for the following information goes to Siraj’s video, so please check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siraj reads anything between 10 to 20 research papers a week! But he doesn’t have any graduate degree, so this is the result of purely getting better over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Collective University is the Internet. Remember this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-resources-can-i-use&quot;&gt;What Resources Can I Use?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siraj finds the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/MachineLearning/&quot;&gt;Machine Learning SubReddit &lt;/a&gt;most useful when it comes to discovering relevant and refreshing research papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, he often uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arxiv-sanity.com/&quot;&gt;ArXiv Sanity&lt;/a&gt;, which is a more user-friendly version of the traditional &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/&quot;&gt;ArXiv.org&lt;/a&gt; made by the Cornell University. Both of these contain millions of advanced papers, so they should be used in conjunction. I can filter the results based on what interests me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another website is a blog made by an Australian machine learning engineer, who puts blog posts that are very descriptive and hands-on. It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://machinelearningmastery.com/how-to-research-a-machine-learning-algorithm/&quot;&gt;Machine Learning Mastery&lt;/a&gt;, and this website is my favourite. The good thing about this is that he emphasizes practicality over complicatedness, so if you follow his article, you will easily be able to make an implementation yourself. Research papers can sometimes be daunting or difficult to try out by yourself. He also sells amazing books that teaches you with easy explanations (I have them and they are outstanding), but most of the content can be found within the blog. I recommend using this website to gain confidence in machine learning (which I need) by learning the concepts fast and building your own models to solidify knowledge. Once the foundation is set, it would be much easier to read more advanced research papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DIY is also important!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-do-i-choose-what-research-papers-to-read&quot;&gt;How do I choose what Research Papers to Read?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set a small goal each week - what do I want to learn more about?  Is it activation models? Hyper-parameter tuning? Siraj can go through difficult papers much better if he has a motivation and a real reason to dive into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-do-i-actually-read-the-paper-is-there-a-specific-method&quot;&gt;How do I “Actually” Read the Paper? Is There a Specific Method?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! Siraj calls it the &lt;em&gt;3-pass Method&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Step:&lt;/strong&gt; Just skim through the paper. Read the title and see if it is interesting. Read the abstract. If it is still intriguing, the skim through the entire paper. Read headings and subheadings, but ignore the math entirely. Read the conclusion as well as references, to see if there are any research papers that you already read. Only attempt to get a overarching view on what the paper intends to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to see if the paper is “worth your time.” You can even look at Reddit to see the initial reactions of people who already read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Step:&lt;/strong&gt; Re-Read, more critically, taking notes as well (summary!). Read all the English text, and get a high-level understanding of the math. If you cannot understand anything, it might be a sign that you need a little bit more foundation. But never give up! There must be some articles online made by some other people that explain the concepts more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very Important: When I read about the experiment, consider if the results are repeatable, backed up with good evidence. Hopefully, there is some relevant code along with the paper that I can use by myself, most likely available on GitHub. Read the code and try to run the code locally to replicate the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Step:&lt;/strong&gt; Siraj has a Jupyter Notebook full of notes and images that help explain concepts. He says that teaching is the best way to retain information, which I agree, so I will write blog posts about every research paper I read! I hope you will do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third step is all about breaking down the math further. Understand every part of the math, using Wikipedia to understand any ambiguous concepts. If Siraj is “really ambitious,” he also tries to “replicate the paper programmatically, using hyper parameters settings and equations that it describes,” but I honestly do not understand what he means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I hope the major points are laid out nicely in this article. Thank you for tuning in, and I will come back with an interesting research article soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/how-to-read-research-papers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/how-to-read-research-papers</guid>
        
        <category>howto</category>
        
        <category>summary</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Distractions in times of a Global Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I noticed that the New York Times changed a lot after the birth of COVID-19. Every day, it shared films that we can binge-watch at home, along with new recipes, books, and even video games. This “At Home” section stayed on the front page along with the regular serious articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was strange to me how a newspaper emphasizes that “not losing your mind” is important, telling me that distractions are necessary right now. It surely felt human, but I did not buy that idea. I would rather “enrich my mind” by using the hours at home to do something meaningful. My school switched entirely to online learning until the end of this school year, and I was sure that there would be myriad ways to diversify my indoor life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my goal to create meaning resulted in sitting in front of my computer all day long. Making music with my friends required a keyboard, GarageBand, and Adobe Premiere Pro. Working on Data Science projects meant researching online and crunching data with Atom. Running outside with a mask was the only outdoor activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero commute time gave me great flexibility in my schedule. It was not long ago when I minimized such “unproductive” time, listening to Ted Talks on the way to school and flipping over Hanzi Flashcards while returning. But I realized now that physically being in different settings has always ventilated my mind so that it can be filled with refreshing new tasks. Instead of enjoying the maximum productivity that I hoped for, I started looking into the recommendations by the New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fulfilled the need to unwind here and there—ventilating my mind—with screen time again. Youtube, Netflix, iPad games, and more. They were like energy-boost drinks that have an immediate effect, and I didn’t need to move an inch to enjoy them. My desk had all I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../post-images/2020-6-16-distractions-covid-19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My workspace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only if these energy drinks were not addictive…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly lost the sense of distinction between energy-boosts and productive work. Walking and working were two very different things before the virus, but everything now was under the broad category of “screen time.” After hours pass in any given day, it became too common for me to summarise what I have achieved. When I went through History in Google Chrome a week ago, the redness of Youtube and Netflix dominated the website list. The elegance of the New York Times logo and WaitButWhy faded. I even lost a sense of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to justify my relationship with distractions every day. I am in the middle of a serious global pandemic, and as the New York Times said, let’s just not “lose my mind.” What else can I do? What else &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dissatisfaction with myself grew daily as I tried to enlighten the day with an endless array of momentary entertainment. Distractions seemed to be almost paralyzing me, removing any space for my mind to wander. Does “not losing my mind” mean constantly distracting it? This feels wrong. Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the New York Times woke me up. On its front page one day, I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/12/opinion/sunday/black-america-racism-refugee.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Opinion&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot;&gt;a powerful and moving article.&lt;/a&gt; It was a personal reflection by Tiffanie Drayton, who fled the US due to unstoppable racism and the danger that black citizens face in the country. A mixture of emotions hit me as I visualized the heart-wrenching descriptions of protests and the ongoing attacks against black Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as racism was “too much” for her to bear, the shame I felt about myself overwhelmed me. I did not know anything about George Floyd nor the reasons why people are out on the streets. I did not know how the “Black Lives Matter” movement sprung up. I had to google everything up because the author simply did not need to define these current events, knowing that it is already in the minds of millions. While these people were heroically calling for change, I was stuck in my room disconnected from the world, only plugged into irrelevant distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I was like a newsboy. I closely followed the upcoming US Election, and I watched every single Democratic Debate from start to finish. I marveled at the endorsement of two candidates by the New York Times. I also watched Joe Biden going up and down, finally securing his place. The more I stayed away from current news, the more I became indifferent to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unwinding has become more important than ever during this stressful global crisis, but I believe that it should not numb our attention to the outside world. For a data science journalist, current events are sources of inspiration. Too often, distractions also interfere with the momentum of our goals and daily tasks. Writing is a stellar example because it requires us to spend time with sustained and focused effort, which can easily become daunting once distractions take over our minds. The need to think deeply becomes tedious, urging us to visit Youtube for short-and-sweet entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I am distracted, the less I am myself. Distractions are important to unload stress, but I indeed went too far.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/distractions-in-times-of-covid-19</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/distractions-in-times-of-covid-19</guid>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
